<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Chris W Jones]]></title>
  <link href="https://christopherjones.us/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://christopherjones.us/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-08T22:27:15-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://christopherjones.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris W Jones]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chris@christopherjones.us]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tools]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/04/08/tools/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-08T19:45:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/04/08/tools</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I&rsquo;m doing the obligatory post about the tools that I use to program.  Let&rsquo;s start out with the tools I use:<!-- more -->
&ndash; Sublime Text
&ndash; Linux Virtual Machine
&ndash; Git
&ndash; rvm</p>

<p>With those, I can conquer anything thrown my way.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a recent convert to <a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text</a>.  Before that, I mainly used Notepad++.  I love it&rsquo;s speed mainly.  Using Notepad++ with a lot of files in a project causes it to move deathly slow.  I&rsquo;ve yet to notice a slow down in Sublime Text.  In addition, I enjoy the robust plugin support and the theming support.</p>

<p>As linux virtual machines go, I keep one running at <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=3afd2090e2b9">Digital Ocean</a>.  Nothing too massive but one that I use for my development.  I keep my development directory in sync with it using a VPN.  Developing on Windows sucks.  I never know when a package won&rsquo;t run correctly or if there is some weird quirk for installing it.  It&rsquo;s so much easier to just develop in *nix.</p>

<p><a href="https://git-scm.herokuapp.com/">Git</a>, how I love thee.  Git is the version control system that I use.  I&rsquo;ve poked around with Subversion and mercurial too just so that I know them.  My work has been saved more than once because I checked it into the git repository.  Git tracks the changes to the files and allows me to move between versions of the files.  So awesome.</p>

<p>Finally, <a href="https://rvm.io/">rvm</a> for Ruby development.  Using rvm, I can easily manage the version of ruby intalled in my development environment.  I find it super useful when I&rsquo;m working on other projects.  When they are using an older version of ruby for some reason, rvm gracefully switches to their version so that I&rsquo;m developing like them.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all for this week, I hope you enjoyed it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Active Model Serializers]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/api/2015/04/01/using-active-model-serializers/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-01T19:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/52in52/api/2015/04/01/using-active-model-serializers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Boy, this one is late. I blame moving. Hilary and I finally got the keys to our new place and have started moving in.  Last time I wrote about programming, I discussed APIs. In this post, I want to continue in the same theme and discuss implementing an API in a Rails application.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Rails has a great, simple way to output standard JSON instead of an HTML document.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>app/controllers/flashcards_controller.rb </span></figcaption>
<div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">FlashcardsController</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="no">ApplicationController</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">index</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">render</span> <span class="ss">json</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="no">Deck</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">all</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>That block of code would output all of the Decks in the database as a JSON object.  The problem is that it doesn&rsquo;t give you much control over it.  What if you had a relation where each deck <code>has_many: cards</code>?  That controller wouldn&rsquo;t give you any indication about it.  That&rsquo;s where a handy gem called <a href="https://github.com/rails-api/active_model_serializers">active_model_serializers</a> comes in.  Active model serializers gives you very fine control over what is output in JSON.</p>

<p>The way it works is you create a file in the serializers directory for each model.  Then you can define exactly which attributes are output as JSON as well as how they&rsquo;re output.  This is what a simple AMS looks like for a model Deck(id: number, title:string, public: boolean, card_id: number).</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>app/serializers/deck_serializer.rb </span></figcaption>
<div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">DeckSerializer</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="no">ActiveModel</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">Serializer</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">embed</span> <span class="ss">:ids</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">attributes</span> <span class="ss">:id</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">:title</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">has_many</span> <span class="ss">:cards</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The attribute line specifies which parts of the model to expose in your API.  The has_many line tells AMS to expose that there decks and cards are related.  The neat part of this is the <code>embed :ids</code> line.  Taking that line out AMS will include the cards that are associated with the deck in the JSON response.  With that line in, AMS will simply give you the ids instead of the whole card object.</p>

<p>I love using AMS for creating JSON responses.  Next week I&rsquo;ll combine what I talked about APIs with AMS and Grape.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Pause This Week]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/03/25/on-pause-this-week/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-25T21:10:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/03/25/on-pause-this-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was planning on writing another post about creating an API but I&rsquo;m exhausted.  This weekend Hilary and I moved our worldly possesions into some <a href="http://www.uhaul.com/UBox/">U-Haul U-Boxes</a>.  We finished moving out of our apartment today and as of 2pm, we&rsquo;re officially homeless for a week until our new townhome is available.</p>

<p>With all this flurry of activity, I just don&rsquo;t have it in me to write a blog post about how to create an API for a website using the Grape gem.  Check back next week for a new article!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating an API]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/api/2015/03/18/creating-an-api/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-18T19:25:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/52in52/api/2015/03/18/creating-an-api</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Part 1 in my series on creating an API in Rails.  Here&rsquo;s <a href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/api/2015/04/01/using-grape-api/">part 2</a>.</p>

<p>This week, I have been working hard to add an <abbr title="Application Programming Interface">API</abbr> to a website that I wrote.  I&rsquo;m going to explain what an API is and why I want one for this website.</p>

<p>When you visit a website, your browser uses a protocol called HTTP.  HTTP is made up of verbs that describe interactions with the server.  When you visit <a href="http://christopherjones.us"><a href="http://christopherjones.us">http://christopherjones.us</a></a>, your browser uses the HTTP verb GET because you want to &ldquo;get&rdquo; the page.  When you log in to a website, your browser uses the verb POST like you&rsquo;re mailing the data to the server.  There are a bunch of other verbs used as well but I&rsquo;m not going to get into them.<!-- more -->  After doing a GET request, the server located at <a href="http://christopherjones.us"><a href="http://christopherjones.us">http://christopherjones.us</a></a> responds with the page you requested, its response will look something like:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='html'><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;html&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;head&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;title&gt;</span>Chris W Jones<span class="nt">&lt;/title&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;/head&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;body&gt;</span>...<span class="nt">&lt;/body&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;/html&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Believe it or not, that response is hard for a computer to read.  The difficulty comes from the fact that anything can be in between those <code>&lt;body&gt;</code> tags.  It could be a picture of a cat or it could be the entire text of the Illiad.  Computers don&rsquo;t do so well with that much ambigity which is why developers use APIs.  APIs are the computer&rsquo;s interface to a website.</p>

<p>When designing an API, developers think about what kinds of information that users will want to use from their site.  For example in my Bibliophilum website, I might have an API endpoint that allows users to request the books in their library.  Another endpoint might allow users to see which books are currently loaned from their library.  When a user wants the list of their books, they&rsquo;ll do a GET request to that endpoint and the server will respond with something that a computer can understand like:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='json'><span class='line'><span class="p">[</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="err">id:</span> <span class="err">1,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="err">title:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Moby Dick&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="err">author:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Herman Melville&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="err">id:</span> <span class="err">2,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="err">title:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Accelerando&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="err">author:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Charles Stross&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">]</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The format of the response from the server is usually documented and doesn&rsquo;t change.  This allows the computer using the API to understand the data received.</p>

<p>I really wanted to develop an API for this website because of a new trend in web development.  This trend is towards using a single page to serve the whole website and requesting the different pages in the background.  Gmail is a good example of a single page application (SPA) like this.</p>

<p>In the traditional client/server architecture, your browser sends a GET request to my server.  My server responds with the page.  You click the link which sends another GET request for that page which my server responds with.  In the SPA architecture, your browser sends a GET request for my main page.  After that, when you click a link on the page the page rewrites itself to be the new page, requesting additional data from the server as needed.</p>

<p>The main benefit of using this SPA is that the processing power my server would use to generate the page is offloaded to your browser saving me bandwidth and electricity.  The API comes into this when the SPA requets additional data as needed.  It needs to be able to understand the data so it queries the API.</p>

<p>That is an overview of what APIs are and one way that they&rsquo;re used.  Next week, I&rsquo;m going to explore a specific way to implement an API in Rails using a gem called Grape.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Busy Life]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/03/12/busy-life/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-12T21:01:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/03/12/busy-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Life Is getting busy for me. In about two weeks my wife, Hilary, and I will be moving. In addition to that, I have an astronomy class that just finished and a discrete math class that starts on Monday. I also have a busy schedule when I&rsquo;m at work.</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t the first time that I have found the pace of life picking up.  I have found that when I get stressed out about having a lot on my plate, the best thing I can do is control what I can and try to not let the rest bother me.  That means that I have been making schedules and lists for the upcoming move and taking things in stride when the don&rsquo;t work out like I want.  For example, a townhouse that we were interested was pulled off the market the day that we were going to view it. Frustrating.</p>

<p>Two points that I always keep on my schedule though are reading and programming.  Sometimes <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:magikid/t:feedly/">they overlap</a> when I get especially busy. Currently, I&rsquo;m reading <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/913989470">Murder at the Vicarage</a> by Agatha Christie.  It&rsquo;s a little outside my usual genre of hard sci-fi/space opera but I&rsquo;m enjoying it so far.  It&rsquo;s going to be a quick read.</p>

<p>As for programming, I&rsquo;m still working on my bibliophilium site but slowly. I want to start correctly so that I don&rsquo;t get a few months in and wish I had done things differently.  That involves researching implementations.  Also, moving kind of eats into my programming time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Committal]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/03/04/projects/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-04T20:13:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/03/04/projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have had a lot of problems with starting projects and not following through.  It took me about a year to work through the Ruby koans <small><a href="http://rubykoans.com/">official site</a>|<a href="https://github.com/magikid/my-ruby-koans">my code</a></small>.  And they were simple programming exercises designed to introduce you to the language.  <strong>I say no more</strong>.</p>

<p>This is the year that I stop starting without finishing, at least where programming is involved.  I have recently started a new project that I intend to be a sort-of showcase for my website building skills.  So far, I just have the idea but I want to start it right from the very beginning.  To that end, before I write a single line of code, I will be writing a <a href="https://github.com/magikid/bibliophilium/wiki/functional-spec">functional spec</a> which lays out the user interaction with the site.  It is much easier to pick out issues with the design when they&rsquo;re just ideas on paper.  This will be completed by next Wednesday (11 March 2015).</p>

<p>An example of when writing a spec first came in handy.  I recently started a new project at work.  It will be a fairly simple site to create but it has some very demanding customers.  Before I started to write the code for their website, I sat down and wrote a spec for their site.  I laid out all the different pages of the website.  I wrote down likely use scenarios for the website.  I put in things that I wouldn&rsquo;t be supporting during development.</p>

<p>One of the customers came to visit me and discuss his ideas for the website.  Because I had already formulated my ideas for user interactions, I was able to show him that we were already on the same page in our thinking.  I was also able to assure him that I didn&rsquo;t want to obliterate his current workflow and destroy his productivity with my design.  The best part for me was not having to completely explain myself to him since I&rsquo;d already done that in the document.  I was able to send him a link and say, read it yourself.</p>

<p>Back to my library project: the idea came for this site came to me because of the lack of decent library software.  No seriously.  Look around if you don&rsquo;t believe me.  I just want a decent website that is mobile friendly to manage my books.  It would be great if it integrated with Amazon to pull in book covers too.  That in a nutshell is my new project.  I will be building a library management website.  I&rsquo;m sure this won&rsquo;t be my last post on the subject.</p>

<p>For the programmers in the audience, here&rsquo;s what my thinking is for that side of the house.  I&rsquo;d love to use modern programming standards for this.  The back end will be coded using my beloved Ruby language.  I haven&rsquo;t decided if I will use a full <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> stack or a Rack application like <a href="https://intridea.github.io/grape/">Grape</a> for the API.  I&rsquo;m planning on using the <a href="http://jsonapi.org/">JSON API</a> standard either way for communication with the front end.  Speaking of, I want to use a javascript framework like <a href="https://angularjs.org/">AngularJS</a> for the front end of the website.  That way the website has a very responsive feel to it.  I also would like to learn more about how to create a full website with AngularJS.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been dabbling around with javascript frameworks for about two weeks now.  I&rsquo;ve tried out both AngularJS and <a href="http://emberjs.com/">EmberJS</a>.  I liked the models aspect of Ember more, especially since Angular doesn&rsquo;t have anything close to models.  But after playing around some and exploring both, I think I&rsquo;m going with Angular because of the support for it.  I think it will be easier to solve any problems that I have with it because of its popularity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Blogging Habit]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/02/26/a-blogging-habit/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T18:50:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/52in52/2015/02/26/a-blogging-habit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was listening to <a href="http://www.developertea.com/">Developer Tea</a> yesterday and they were discussing the merits of having a personal blog and marketing yourself as a developer.  I set this blog up last fall as a spot for me to journal.  I think rather than using it as a journal, I will try to discuss mainly programming related topics from now on.</p>

<p>I will be discussing projects that I&rsquo;m working on and new techniques that I&rsquo;m learning.</p>

<p>This week, I&rsquo;ve been exploring <a href="http://joelonsoftware.com/articles/fog0000000043.html">12 Steps To Better Code</a> by Joel Spolsky.  Going through this list, they don&rsquo;t all make sense for me as a long coder working on a website.  I&rsquo;ll still go through all of them.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ol>
<li><p>Do you use source control?</p>

<p>This one is easy.  Yes, I use source control for all of my projects.  It gives me such peace of mind knowing that when I make a mistake, I can quickly and easily fix it.  My source control of choice is <code>git</code> but I won&rsquo;t hold it against anyone for using <code>hg</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>Can you make a build in one step?</p>

<p>For this question, I&rsquo;m going to say that build means deploy the current version of the site.  The answer to this is yes.  I mainly accomplish this by using the correct tools for the correct language.  When I&rsquo;m writing a traditional rails application, I use the asset pipeline.  When I&rsquo;m writing an angular app, I use yo, bower and grunt.  When I&rsquo;m not writing a web app, I still have a script that builds or runs the application.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you make daily builds?</p>

<p>This one is, I guess, yes.  I make daily builds when I&rsquo;m working on a project, especially for web development.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have a bug database?</p>

<p>Yes.  I tend to use GitHub (or at work GitLab) Issues for bug tracking.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you fix bugs before writing new code?</p>

<p>It depends on the schedule.  Since I&rsquo;m a one-man coding shop, I try to balance new features with backlog fixes.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have an up-to-date schedule?</p>

<p>For loose definitions of schedule, yes.  I try to put estimates on the issues that I open and assign them to milestones which have deadlines.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have a spec?</p>

<p>This is a new one I can answer yes to.  I recently (read last week) started writing a spec for my current project.  I haven&rsquo;t started any coding on it.  One of the stakeholders came over and was talking to me about things he would like to see.  Where we differed, it was so easy to update the spec with his requests.</p></li>
<li><p>Do programmers have quiet working conditions?</p>

<p>Yes. Bose QC15&rsquo;s help a lot.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you use the best tools money can buy?</p>

<p>When I&rsquo;m at home I do.  When I&rsquo;m at work, it&rsquo;s a different story.  I have some good tools but I wouldn&rsquo;t say they&rsquo;re the best.  My biggest complaint is that I can&rsquo;t get Sublime Text installed.  I have to resort to using Notepad++.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have testers?</p>

<p>Not really.  I don&rsquo;t always write tests, unit or otherwise.  I&rsquo;ve tried in the past but since until recently I had to resort to Cygwin, that made writing tests impractical.</p></li>
<li><p>Do new candidates write code during their interview?</p>

<p>Not applicable to me.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you do hallway usability testing?</p>

<p>If my wife counts then yes, I do.  She gets tormented by me when I need an average person to test something.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In wrapping up, I came up with 11/12 which Joel says is tolerable.  I have to agree.  I can&rsquo;t complain about my programming conditions.  PS for those of you wondering about my cat Leon, he&rsquo;s doing well.  In my last post, he had developed Feline Diabetes.  It turns out that cats can recover from diabetes.  Scientists aren&rsquo;t sure how but that&rsquo;s what happened to Leon.  He is back to his old licky, annoying self.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feline Diabetes]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/11/04/Feline-Diabetes/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T20:36:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/11/04/Feline-Diabetes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of our cats, Leon, stopped eating this weekend.  He has been eating noticibly less for the past month or two and has gone from 15lbs to 9lbs.  I took him to the vet on Monday.  After blood work and x-rays, he has feline diabetes.  I didn&rsquo;t realize that cats could get diabetes but I guess anything with a pancreas can.  That means a significant change in his (and our) life with cats.  From here on out, we will be giving him twice daily insulin injections for the rest of his life.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m nervous about it.  Not just for Leon&rsquo;s sake but because it&rsquo;s expensive.  Hilary and I have been using <a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/QK4PP9C">YNAB</a> for budgeting for a while now.  For those of you unfamiliar with it, it is a similar idea to budgeting with envelopes but it&rsquo;s all on computers (and mobile devices).  Using YNAB, we have stopped spending on our credit card &mdash; until today that is.  I&rsquo;m glad that we had an emergency fund going for just such an event.  It was a little less than we needed but I anticipate that the amount we put on the credit card today will be paid off within the next 2-3 months without lowering our standard of living too much.</p>

<p>From what I have read on the internet, the cost of supporting a cat with feline diabetes is around $250 every six months in supplies not including any vet trips which seem to be fairly regular too.  Just like in humans, we have to track glucose levels in the blood to give a good dose of insulin.  I&rsquo;m hoping to talk to the vet and arrange for home testing.  The internet seems to think that there is no need to visit the vet for these types of simple tests.  It is the exact same as glucose monitoring in humans.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[16 Book Blurb]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/24/16-Book-Blurb/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-24T20:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/24/16-Book-Blurb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 16: Imagine that someone has decided to write a book about your life, just up to this point. What would the cover blurb say? Be honest here. Is it kind of boring? Are you happy with it? Now imagine what you’d like that blurb to say at the end of your life. What changes need to made for that to happen?</em></p>

<p>This prompt seems to think that up until this point in my life, I have done nothing interesting or noteworthy.  I wonder if that doesn&rsquo;t speak to who the author thinks is their target audience.  Personally, I feel like they&rsquo;re talking down to me.  I think that if someone were to write a book about my life up to this point, it might not be Harry Potter but it would be better than some of the trash that I&rsquo;ve read in the last 5 years.  Depending on how the rest of my life goes, my life could rank up there with many well known figures.  Dropped out of college and joined the military?  That sounds like presidential material to me.  Not to mention my job in the Air Force and all the interesting things that I do there.  Ultimately, I&rsquo;d say that life is going how I want it to for now.  I think that having a plan helps me to be more satisfied with life than some of my contemporaries.  I know where I&rsquo;ve been, I&rsquo;ve learned some lessons, and I ultimately see where I want to go (if not the exact route).</p>

<p>As for the blurb at the end of my life, I&rsquo;d just like it to say that I was happy.  Since my own happiness is within my control, I believe that my goal will be fulfilled.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Cabinet of Invisible Counselors]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/22/15-Cabinet-of-Invisible-Counselors/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-22T21:03:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/22/15-Cabinet-of-Invisible-Counselors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 15: Come up with your own Cabinet of Invisible Counselors. There are innumerable great men from history who we can learn from today. When thinking about your life or pondering some question or problem, yes, go to actual mentors and friends, but also take in the advice of men of yore. Write out who you would have on your list and what you admire about them. Having trouble coming up with a list? The comments in the post should offer plenty of ideas.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>On my cabinet of invisible counselors, I would at least have Teddy Roosevelt on it.  I&rsquo;m not sure who else from history that I would turn to for advice.  I suppose that if it is an imaginary counsel, I&rsquo;d also ask for the Buddha.</p>

<p>I still haven&rsquo;t given this post much thought.  I suppose that I would choose Teddy due to his pragmatism.  I&rsquo;ve recently read a biography of him and he seems to have always looked for a level-headed solution to the problems that faced him.</p>

<p>And the Buddha would make it on my counsel because of his wisdom.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[14 Book Review]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/06/07/14-Book-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-07T20:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/06/07/14-Book-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 14: Write a review of some form of entertainment you recently took in. Whether book or movie or TV show or Broadway play, write out what you liked and didn’t like about it. Was the acting/writing good? Could you follow the story? Is there anything you can take from it about life, or was it purely entertainment? This is often one of the most enjoyable entries to write, as it’s especially fun (and quite nostalgic) to go back and read these in the future. I can imagine that 10 years from now I will thoroughly appreciate my thoughts from this week on Roy Baumeister’s Is There Anything Good About Men?.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>For this I&rsquo;m going to write about A Wrinkle In Time.  Since I recently finished it.  I picked it up because I remembered reading it as a child and being enthralled by it.  Even as young as I was, I made the connection between &ldquo;wrinkling&rdquo; and &ldquo;wormholes&rdquo;.  I think my early fascination with the book is what led me to be disappointed with this read as an adult.</p>

<p>I found the book to be simple and childish.  None of the topics that I found interesting were explored enough for me.  For instance, I would have liked more in-depth knowledge of the relationship between Charles Wallace and Meg.  While Meg professed that she and Charles Wallace had a deep relationship, I felt that since this book was from her perspective, I would have liked to see more into her mind.</p>

<p>Overall, it was a good book but I don&rsquo;t think that I&rsquo;ll pick it up again any time soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Mind Dump]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/30/13-Mind-Dump/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-30T20:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/30/13-Mind-Dump</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 13: Perform a mind dump of everything you’re worried about. From the leaky dishwasher to your family member’s poor health — get it all out. Dwight D. Eisenhower did it, and it significantly helped him manage his stress. Just as your body needs to… cleanse itself of waste, so does your mind every once in a while. Getting all your stressors on paper may alleviate some of that pressure. Use <a href="http://wiki.43folders.com/index.php/Trigger_List">David Allen’s GTD trigger</a> list to help you out.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;m reading through this list and I think this could get quite long.  I guess just starting is the way to go.</p>

<p>About the professional side of the house, I have only one project that I&rsquo;ve started which I need to finish and that is my Pomodoro webpage.  It is mostly done but I want to publish it before I consider it done.  I am planning on starting a documentation project for my new position.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t recall any commitments or promises to anyone in this list.  The closes that I can think of would be that I need to organize and develop a list of bullets for my supervisor.</p>

<p>I have only one professional communication to make and that is in relation to my upcoming business trip.  I need to make contact with them and confirm arrangements.</p>

<p>Under this planning/organizing heading, I do need to formalize my position goals and objectives with my team lead.  I&rsquo;m not sure what is expected of my job-wise.</p>

<p>I need to reset my voicemail password.</p>

<p>I need to find someone with the key to my drawers.</p>

<p>Under the professional development, one of the bullets is skills to learn.  Since I have more skills to learn at work than I can remember, I&rsquo;ll just write that there are many.</p>

<p>This also reminds me that I wanted to write a resume and have it approved.</p>

<p>Professional wardrobe: I need to get new ribbons, preferably the pre put together ones.  I think there is a link to the website off the BX page.</p>

<p>Starting in on the Personal section.</p>

<p>There are several personal projects that I&rsquo;ve started and not finished:  Ruby Koans, CodeSchool learning Ruby, Wheels Across Anchorage (still), a website redesign, and making beer labels.</p>

<p>Although, I suppose that making beer labels could fall under not started since all I have done it buy the labels, I haven&rsquo;t done anything else.</p>

<p>The only commitment I can recall is to go on a cruise with Hilary.  The next step of which is decide on a cruise and submit the paperwork for it.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have any projects for other organizations but I do have an obligation to the SPCA to attend the volunteer session in June.</p>

<p>Communication to make: Call Yarmuth about White House and Capitol building tours.</p>

<p>The next big upcoming event will be Hilary&rsquo;s birthday in August.  Well, on this list, I suppose that I would count Nikki and Max&rsquo;s wedding, the trip to Rehobeth beach, Brandon and Kelsey&rsquo;s visit, and my Mom&rsquo;s visit, followed finally by our cruise.</p>

<p>Bills need to be paid for June since I won&rsquo;t be here.  I wonder if I can look up balances for most of them?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m waiting on several packages the most important of which is probably my text book for my class starting in June.</p>

<p>Need to buy Windows 8 for my desktop and possibly another HDD.</p>

<p>I need to drop my blues off at the dry cleaners.</p>

<p>Now that I have made it through the list, there is still one big stress on my mind that I don&rsquo;t think has made enough of an impact on this post.  I am leaving for a business trip this week and I am super nervous about it.  I just found out Friday that I will be actually going on it.  It has really reworked my whole little world.  I really hope that Hilary does alright during the time that I am gone.  Since she doesn&rsquo;t drive and seems hesitant to take the bus/MARC, I&rsquo;m worried that she will sit at home all three weeks that I am gone.  All I can do is hope that she doesn&rsquo;t.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[12 Stream of Thought]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/19/12-Stream-of-thought/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-19T21:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/19/12-Stream-of-thought</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 12: Give stream-of-consciousness writing a try. This is where you basically just write out whatever comes into your head at the moment it comes into your head. It can feel bizarre, and it’s certainly not structured, but it can lead to some valuable insights into what’s going on in your mind. I’ll give you a 10-second example from right now, while looking out my window: “Boy, I have a nice-looking grill outside and the weather is beautiful…just what we need after all this cold and snow. That butt looks like a ship from Star Wars… it makes me want to be outside.. maybe I need to spend more time outside and appreciate the fresh air. Perhaps I’ll open a window!” Random? Absolutely. Offering some helpful insight about my desire/need for fresh air? Affirmative. Try this out for 10-15 minutes. You may uncover something — no matter how small — you hadn’t previously realized.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Since I&rsquo;m supposed to be in a steram of thought, I&rsquo;ve engaged hemingway mode on here.  Now I can&rsquo;t correct any mistakes or spelling errors.  Hooray?  I&rsquo;m upposed to be typing everything that goes through my head which right now is mainly, man I&rsquo;m tired and I have to be up at 0530 for running tomorrow.  I thought I would bein bead a while ago but haven&rsquo;t made it there yet.  I&rsquo;m more interested in finding some good aftersahve because even though  I like the lotion, I&rsquo;d liek some thing that also smells good and is an astringent .  I&rsquo;ve been breaking out like a teenagers again lately and it&rsquo;s super annoying.  I winder if anyone wil read this or these entries ever.  I suppose that one day Hilary or my children (when they exist) will bbe able to look through my journal netires the way that I read Granddad&rsquo;s book/journal of WW2.  I&rsquo;m aftaraid that they will think I&rsquo;m unwortyh or unitersting which I supposed I am.  I wouldn&rsquo;t read my own writing which I suppose means that I wshould get better at it.  Hmm.  I&rsquo;ve always been told that Im&#8217; a decent writer but it has been years since Ive serioulsy written anything other thna journal entries.  Maybe I should try writing a shourt story or two once I&rsquo;m donw with these journaling prompts.  The problem I have with stream of conciousness writing is that I&rsquo;ve been trying to practice mindefullness and meditatin (somewhat).  I&rsquo;m pretty good at thinking about notuhing when I want to .  I suppose that means taht I&rsquo;m repressing thoughts which could be a bad thing. It think its ok since I&rsquo;m not repressing them becase someone wants me to but because I want to live in the moment.  I want to make a moment more focused.  Anyway, I&rsquo;m yawning here so I should probbly go to bed.  Another note about writing like this is that I typically write what I&rsquo;m thinking and leave the editing up for later anyway.  I find that I write conversationally.  I write what is in my mind at the time I&rsquo;m writing.  It&rsquo;s like speaking, I don&rsquo;t really think about it, I leave it up to my breain to figure out which words and order to speakin.  Ok really done now .</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[11 Memento Mori]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/05/11-Memento-Mori/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-05T17:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/05/11-Memento-Mori</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 11: Memento mori. “Remember that you will die.” Admittedly, this isn’t the most pleasant topic. There is, however, great benefit in meditating on the reality that at some point, you will in fact die. It motivates you to live the life right now that you want to be living. Meditate on this, and write out your thoughts. Does death scare you? Does it motivate you? It’s okay to be honest.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First of all, I think it&rsquo;s funny that I&rsquo;m instructed to be honest as if I am not usually honest with my thoughts and feelings.</p>

<p>I have thought about death many times.  I suppose that I would call my thoughts about death pragmatic.  It is interesting to think about, as a mental exercise.  I used to think that my feelings on death made me a sociopath &mdash; as I&rsquo;m sure that I&rsquo;ve written before.  It&rsquo;s not that I want to die, I have simply accepted that one day, I will die and I will never know when that day will arrive.  I know that the odds are on my side for living a decently long life.  Just because that I have accepted the fact that one day, I will die, doesn&rsquo;t mean that I avoid risky behaviors.  I certainly don&rsquo;t seek out risky behaviors but I do enjoy some like rock climbing occasionally and skiing.  I try and take reasonable precautions when I am going to engage in some sort of risky behaviors.  I wonder if that isn&rsquo;t just part of maturing.</p>

<p>Thinking about death doesn&rsquo;t motivate or hinder me.  I have read the study of people on their deathbeds where people said their biggest regret was that they didn&rsquo;t work doing something they enjoyed.  I like to tell myself that I am working towards my dream job.  The Air Force is a decent place to work but it&rsquo;s definitely not my favorite.  As for sheer enjoyment, I enjoyed working retail at Christmas more.  The Air Force is just a stepping stone on the path to my career in programming.  Just because I have a day job that I&rsquo;m not thrilled about, I am still working on my programming ability by taking classes towards a CS degree and things like <a href="http://codeschool.com]">Codeschool</a> and <a href="http://rubykoans.org">Koans</a>.  I suppose that you could say that death is motivating me to live a more full life but I don&rsquo;t consciously attribute it to death.  I just want to live a happy life and to live a happy life, you gotta do what you love!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Hero's Journey]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/04/28/10-Heros-Journey/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-28T15:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/04/28/10-Heros-Journey</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 10: Take a look at the <a href="http://www.artofmanliness.com/2013/07/11/heros-journey/">hero’s journey</a>, and identify where you are in that journey. Doing so can help you better understand where you are in life, and help you figure out where to go next. You can take it in the context of your entire life, or you can take it in the context of a certain phase of your life. Either way, you can be sure that you’re part of a greater journey, and knowing what comes next can help guide you along.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>After reading through these stages, I think that I am still in The Ordeal: the central conflict in the story, the big boss fight, where the possibility of death is imminent.</p>

<p>I think that not only because according to the Warrior Ethos, I could have my life put in danger at any time but because if I look at my 20&rsquo;s as the journey, I see joining the Air Force as my main journey that satisfies most of these steps.  The one thing that I find notably absent is the mentor.  I can&rsquo;t say that I&rsquo;ve had a mentor ever.</p>

<p>I suppose the closest person to a mentor that I have is Robert Davis but I have never mentioned it to him and know very little about him.  What I do know is that he lives a life-style that I want to live.  I know that he treats people kindly.  I know that he loves his wife.  I know that he raised a well adjusted son.  When I move back to Louisville, I hope to develop a closer relationship with him.</p>

<p>Looking ahead to exiting the military, there will be a period of adjustment.  In the military, my life is governed by regulations both in and out of uniform.  I can be punished at work for things that happen outside of work.  I worry that when I leave the military, I will be directionless and paralyzed by fear of failure.  I feel that the military provides me a safety net to try things without failing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 My Day]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/04/15/9-Day/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T09:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/04/15/9-Day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 9: On this day, simply write about your day. This may seem especially boring, but write out the events of your day. What time you woke up, what you had for breakfast, what your commute was like, what you did during at work, how you spent your evening. If you’re journaling in the mornings, write about the previous day. The beauty of this exercise is that you may discover something that you hadn’t realized. Maybe you weren’t very productive at work, and reflecting on it can allow you to analyze why. Perhaps you finished a big project on the house when you got home; you can think about what motivated you, how it made you feel to finish something big, etc. Don’t discount the seemingly simple task of writing about your day.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Since I&rsquo;m writing this in the relative morning on 15 April, I&rsquo;m going to journal about 14 April.</p>

<p>I almost woke up early.  I remember picking up my cell phone to check the time at 0500.  I dozed for around 45 minutes until my wrist started vibrating to wake me up.  I love having my FitBit wake me rather than a traditional alarm distrubing Hilary.  As is my usual ritual, I picked up my phone and started reading news on Reddit and looking through pictures on Imgur until 0600 when I dragged myself out of bed for a shower.  This particular morning, I decided to try a new shaving ritual.  On Saturday, I bought some Art of Shaving Pre-shave Oil so I added that to my line-up and decided to shave at the sink.  Overall, I found that adding the pre-shave oil to be thick.  Between it and my psot-shave lotion, my skin feels really oily.  It did give me a good shave though.</p>

<p>I finally made it to work right at 0730.  I had a few tasks on my to-do list but since they totalled three, I decided to stretch them over a few days.  When I first arrived at work, I checked the news on Hacker News and TechMeme.  I read a few articles before deciding to work some.</p>

<p>For tracking my work tasks, I setup a notebook in Onenote.  I&rsquo;m using GTD with it.  I have four sections grouped under GTD: Inbox, To-do, Waiting, Done.  Each new task goes into new page in the Inbox section.  I then prioritize tasks and move them to To-do which is sorted by priority.  If I&rsquo;m waiting on something in order to accomplish a task, it goes to the Waiting secition.  Once done, I move tasks to the Done section.  I also have a separate section, outside of the GTD sections, specifically for visitors or phonecalls so that I can catalog them and route them to the appropriate person.</p>

<p>Today, I was given another task in the morning of picking up MSgt Koonce&rsquo;s and SSgt Harden&rsquo;s picture frames for the ALS hallway.  Once I was done with my morning news reading, I called over to the Arts and Crafts center to make sure they were open and get the details about picking them up.  Since everything seemed to be in order, TSgt Dearinger and I located the receipt for the frames and I drove over to pick them up.</p>

<p>They located the order but said that ALS had failed to pay for the etching on the class, in this case two Air Force symbols per pane of glass.  Since I lacked the autority to give any payment, I made up my mind to head back to the building and report my findings.  As I was walking out the door though, I noticed that I had a receipt in my hand saying that ALS did pay for etched glass.  I went back in.  Upon seeing the receipt and confering with the manager, I was given the frames.  The Arts and Crafts employee told me that ALS was undercharged by $24 but because it was the A&amp;C&rsquo;s mistake, they would let it slide this time.  Triumphantly returning, I mounted the new frames on the wall in their places of honor.</p>

<p>Upon finishing my task for the day, I was back to filling my time with internet activities until lunch.</p>

<p>Once lunchtime was upon the school, I decided to pay Hilary a visit so that I could see her for the day since she wouldn&rsquo;t be getting off until 2100.  I also wanted to change from Blue into PT gear since it was quite warm, around 80F.  She was thrilled to see me and we chatted some before I headed off to try and accomplish a personal errand.  I went the long way around to Military Clothing since I&rsquo;ve recived three new ribbons in as many weeks.  Lo and behold, they are open six days a week and Monday is the day they are closed.  Curses.  I turned around and drove back to the school house to eat some lunch.</p>

<p>After eating, I responded to an email requesting more information for my clearance and fielded a phonecall from an investigator working on Cypert&rsquo;s investigation.  I filled the rest of my day with internet nonesense until PT.</p>

<p>PT was uneventful and an ok workout.  TSgt Dearinger introduced me to the students so that they knew what I was doing hanging around the school house.</p>

<p>I headed home after PT and took a quick shower.  Before my shower, I figured out how to unlock the thermostat and adjusted the A/C settings.  After my shower, I booted my desktop (TheProfessor) and set about organizing my TV library which was looking prettty bad.  It was showing that Game of Thrones was Transformers.  I worked on updating the metadata and renaming shows until around 2000 when I realized that I needed to eat some food.  I made (relativly fresh) spaghetti with meat sauce.  I&rsquo;ve never had non-dried spaghetti so it was a new experience.  It definitly tastes different.  I want to try it again before deciding if I like it or not.  Hilary was going to be getting off soon so I watched some Adventure Time while eating and se off to pick
her up.</p>

<p>I opened the door to head out and a letter fluttered to the ground addressed to our apartment.  It was from Flats170 asking that we declutter our deck.</p>

<p>When we returned home, we chatted some while she ate and then I went to bed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[8 Career]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/30/8-Career/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-30T15:30:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/30/8-Career</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 8: Take some time today to reflect on your career. Jot down a timeline of it, including all the ups and downs. What was your best experience? And the worst? What would you like your future to look like, in terms of your career? If you’re a young man and haven’t started in yet, focus on that future part. What do you want your work to look like?</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&lsquo;&rsquo;&lsquo;Timeline:&rsquo;&lsquo;&rsquo;
14 April 2009 &ndash; Enlist in USAF
14 June 2009  &ndash; Graduate BMT
01 July 2009  &ndash; Start DLI in Russian Basic Class
04 July 2010  &ndash; Finish Russian course in top 10 of class</p>

<pre><code>            with 3.8 GPA
</code></pre>

<p>17 Nov 2010   &ndash; Finish Goodfellow training
01 Jan 2011   &ndash; Arrive at Elmendorf AFB.
15 May 2011   &ndash; Finally certified in position, start</p>

<pre><code>            working on the floor on Nautilus (Doing 
            5x8s).
</code></pre>

<p>01 Jun 2011   &ndash; Assigned to Baker watch working Panama</p>

<pre><code>            schedule with 12 hour shifts. 
            (Work, work,  off,  off, work, work, work)
            (Off , off , work, work,  off, off,  off)
            Every month, we switched from days to 
            nights, or nights to days.  It was very 
            difficult on me and I worked this schedule 
            until Feb 2013 when I left Alaska.  The 
            best part about working this schedule was 
            that on nights, I had plenty of time to 
            work on programming projects or learn in 
            general.
</code></pre>

<p>01 Feb 2013   &ndash; Watch schedule was changed to two halves</p>

<pre><code>            of shift, each working 5x8.  I was working 
            Su-Th.  It would be an outright lie to say 
            that I was instrumental in implementing 
            this plan.  I was one of many who helped 
            develop it though and thanks to our 
            receptive leadership, we were able to 
            implement it.
</code></pre>

<p>14 Feb 2013   &ndash; Reenlisted for four years with bonus.
01 May 2013   &ndash; Took Staff test and missed it by 5 points
19 Jan 2014   &ndash; Moved to Fort Meade, MD working at the 29</p>

<pre><code>            IS.
</code></pre>

<p>Mar 2014      &ndash; Took ALS.  Did well in course although I</p>

<pre><code>            didn't pick up any awards, my classmates 
            thought I should have.
</code></pre>

<p>I still feel like I haven&rsquo;t been here very long but I suppose that I know some things about the Air Force if not my job.  My highest point was when I scored a 2+/3 on my Russian DLPT.  My lowest point was the day that I was passed over for a job based not on my qualifications but because I was deemed to important to let go.  As it stands in my life right now, I could see doing this job for 20 years.  I&rsquo;m not sure that I would be fulfilled if I did though.  It all depends on what my actual job turns out to be.  In an ideal world, I would like to program all day long and make good money doing it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[7 Weekly Review]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/22/7-Day-7-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-22T17:03:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/22/7-Day-7-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 7: You’ve made it one week! Reflect on what this newfound practice has been like. Getting through the first seven consecutive days is truly the hardest part. Have you enjoyed it? Has it been difficult? Has it been what you expected?</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<pre><code>Part of this doesn't apply to me since I'm not journaling daily but rather weekly.  I have enjoyed journaling weekly.  I especially like this prompt format and in the future, I may reuse some of these prompts if I can't think of anything to write about.  For the most part, writing has been easy for me as usual.  
The hardest part has been getting a good number in [Beeminder](beeminder.com) so that I would remember that I needed to journal.  I have found that putting up $5 is good incentive to get me to journal.  And not just journaling has encouraged by Beeminder.  I have also started studying Russian more due to it.  Although $5 isn't a lot, it is certainly motivating enough since if I fall off the path, I don't even get something out of that money.
Journaling has been exactly what I expected and wanted.  I was looking for a way for me to express my personality and thought processes in a written fashion.  I really enjoyed reading Granddad's story of what he did in WWII.  What I was left with after reading it though, was questions about the why's behind his decisions so even though I am not doing anything (too) exciting with my life, I want anyone reading this to understand why I made the decisions I did and what kind of person that I am.

And now for something completely different.  I am currently in ALS.  I have been working my butt off this week.  It was the fourth of five weeks so we had several writing assignments and tests.  I passed them all (so far) and was looking forward to a relaxing weekend but it wasn't meant to be.  I was forced to wake up at my normal weekday alarm of 0530 so that I could be at a volunteer event in DC for 0700.  I am so exhausted and out of it that I wonder if this weekend will be rejuvenatory at all.  I just hope that tomorrow I can lounge around and casually study.
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[6 Quote Thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/10/6-Quote-Thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T21:03:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/10/6-Quote-Thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 6: Pick a quote from our 80-ish quotes on manhood and reflect on why it stands out to you. Does it reflect a man that you aren’t yet, but hope to be? Does one of them remind you of a great man in your life who you’ve tried to model? If you can’t seem to reflect on a single quote, just take the time to write out a few of them that you like. Doing so will keep them top-of-mind and perhaps lead to some thoughts later down the road.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>“We do not admire the man of timid peace. We admire the man who embodies victorious effort; the man who never wrongs his neighbor, who is prompt to help a friend, but who has those virile qualities necessary to win in the stern strife of actual life.” –Theodore Roosevelt</p>

<p>I chose this quote by Teddy Roosevelt.  I&rsquo;m not sure why but it really jumped out at me.  What I like about it is that it is about both helping others as well as being made of something strong in order to persevere.  I also see it as an ideal to strive towards which I think is what helps me so much in the Air Force.  Though I don&rsquo;t want them to tell me how to think or what to do, for now their values align with mine so I can&rsquo;t complain too much.  I think this quote shows exactly how great Roosevelt was.  For being seen as such an outdoors-man, he was surprisingly intellectual.  I can&rsquo;t wait to begin reading my biography of him.</p>

<p>There is another quote that I found that resonates with my interest in increasing my discipline by Marcus Aurelias: &ldquo;If unwilling to rise in the morning, say to thyself, ‘I awake to do the work of a man.&lsquo;&rdquo;  I am going to try and remind myself of this every morning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Unsent Letter]]></title>
    <link href="https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/02/5-Unsent-Letter/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T08:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/03/02/5-Unsent-Letter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Write a letter to a loved one</strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Dear Grandmother and Granddad,</p>

<p>I was never old enough to talk to you and ask you questions while you were around and lucid.  I have so many but I also have things that I want to tell you.</p>

<p>Granddad, I joined the Air Force.  I have so many questions about your time in the service.  I read through your biography.  It was so interesting.  I am so proud to call you family.  Thank you for serving our country.  What rank were you when you separated?  What was the enlisted force like?  After you separated, I know that you went back to school and started teaching.  How was that?  Do you have any success stories from teaching?  I know that you greatly influenced my dad in going into teaching.  I wish that he could find a teaching position he was happy in.  I wish that I had known you more as an adult so that I could have talked with you about life.</p>

<p>Grandmother, I feel like I don&rsquo;t know you at all.  I only know that you always kept some sort of cookie or candy in a jar in the dining room.  How was your time working for the state government?  Did you enjoy what you did?  What exactly did you do? Did you ever face sexual discrimination in the workplace?</p>

<p>I suppose that all of these questions will forever remain unanswered since you both passed away several years ago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
