<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Aom | Chris W Jones]]></title>
  <link href="http://christopherjones.us/blog/categories/aom/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://christopherjones.us/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-26T19:06:23-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://christopherjones.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris W Jones]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chris@christopherjones.us]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Feline Diabetes]]></title>
    <link href="http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/11/04/Feline-Diabetes/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-04T20:36:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/11/04/Feline-Diabetes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of our cats, Leon, stopped eating this weekend.  He has been eating noticibly less for the past month or two and has gone from 15lbs to 9lbs.  I took him to the vet on Monday.  After blood work and x-rays, he has feline diabetes.  I didn&rsquo;t realize that cats could get diabetes but I guess anything with a pancreas can.  That means a significant change in his (and our) life with cats.  From here on out, we will be giving him twice daily insulin injections for the rest of his life.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m nervous about it.  Not just for Leon&rsquo;s sake but because it&rsquo;s expensive.  Hilary and I have been using (YNAB)[<a href="http://ynab.refr.cc/QK4PP9C">http://ynab.refr.cc/QK4PP9C</a>] for budgeting for a while now.  For those of you unfamiliar with it, it is a similar idea to budgeting with envelopes but it&rsquo;s all on computers (and mobile devices).  Using YNAB, we have stopped spending on our credit card &mdash; until today that is.  I&rsquo;m glad that we had an emergency fund going for just such an event.  It was a little less than we needed but I anticipate that the amount we put on the credit card today will be paid off within the next 2-3 months without lowering our standard of living too much.</p>

<p>From what I have read on the internet, the cost of supporting a cat with feline diabetes is around $250 every six months in supplies not including any vet trips which seem to be fairly regular too.  Just like in humans, we have to track glucose levels in the blood to give a good dose of insulin.  I&rsquo;m hoping to talk to the vet and arrange for home testing.  The internet seems to think that there is no need to visit the vet for these types of simple tests.  It is the exact same as glucose monitoring in humans.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[16 Book Blurb]]></title>
    <link href="http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/24/16-Book-Blurb/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-24T20:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/24/16-Book-Blurb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 16: Imagine that someone has decided to write a book about your life, just up to this point. What would the cover blurb say? Be honest here. Is it kind of boring? Are you happy with it? Now imagine what you’d like that blurb to say at the end of your life. What changes need to made for that to happen?</em></p>

<p>This prompt seems to think that up until this point in my life, I have done nothing interesting or noteworthy.  I wonder if that doesn&rsquo;t speak to who the author thinks is their target audience.  Personally, I feel like they&rsquo;re talking down to me.  I think that if someone were to write a book about my life up to this point, it might not be Harry Potter but it would be better than some of the trash that I&rsquo;ve read in the last 5 years.  Depending on how the rest of my life goes, my life could rank up there with many well known figures.  Dropped out of college and joined the military?  That sounds like presidential material to me.  Not to mention my job in the Air Force and all the interesting things that I do there.  Ultimately, I&rsquo;d say that life is going how I want it to for now.  I think that having a plan helps me to be more satisfied with life than some of my contemporaries.  I know where I&rsquo;ve been, I&rsquo;ve learned some lessons, and I ultimately see where I want to go (if not the exact route).</p>

<p>As for the blurb at the end of my life, I&rsquo;d just like it to say that I was happy.  Since my own happiness is within my control, I believe that my goal will be fulfilled.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Cabinet of Invisible Counselors]]></title>
    <link href="http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/22/15-Cabinet-of-Invisible-Counselors/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-22T21:03:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/07/22/15-Cabinet-of-Invisible-Counselors</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 15: Come up with your own Cabinet of Invisible Counselors. There are innumerable great men from history who we can learn from today. When thinking about your life or pondering some question or problem, yes, go to actual mentors and friends, but also take in the advice of men of yore. Write out who you would have on your list and what you admire about them. Having trouble coming up with a list? The comments in the post should offer plenty of ideas.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>On my cabinet of invisible counselors, I would at least have Teddy Roosevelt on it.  I&rsquo;m not sure who else from history that I would turn to for advice.  I suppose that if it is an imaginary counsel, I&rsquo;d also ask for the Buddha.</p>

<p>I still haven&rsquo;t given this post much thought.  I suppose that I would choose Teddy due to his pragmatism.  I&rsquo;ve recently read a biography of him and he seems to have always looked for a level-headed solution to the problems that faced him.</p>

<p>And the Buddha would make it on my counsel because of his wisdom.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[14 Book Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/06/07/14-Book-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-07T20:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/06/07/14-Book-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 14: Write a review of some form of entertainment you recently took in. Whether book or movie or TV show or Broadway play, write out what you liked and didn’t like about it. Was the acting/writing good? Could you follow the story? Is there anything you can take from it about life, or was it purely entertainment? This is often one of the most enjoyable entries to write, as it’s especially fun (and quite nostalgic) to go back and read these in the future. I can imagine that 10 years from now I will thoroughly appreciate my thoughts from this week on Roy Baumeister’s Is There Anything Good About Men?.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>For this I&rsquo;m going to write about A Wrinkle In Time.  Since I recently finished it.  I picked it up because I remembered reading it as a child and being enthralled by it.  Even as young as I was, I made the connection between &ldquo;wrinkling&rdquo; and &ldquo;wormholes&rdquo;.  I think my early fascination with the book is what led me to be disappointed with this read as an adult.</p>

<p>I found the book to be simple and childish.  None of the topics that I found interesting were explored enough for me.  For instance, I would have liked more in-depth knowledge of the relationship between Charles Wallace and Meg.  While Meg professed that she and Charles Wallace had a deep relationship, I felt that since this book was from her perspective, I would have liked to see more into her mind.</p>

<p>Overall, it was a good book but I don&rsquo;t think that I&rsquo;ll pick it up again any time soon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Mind Dump]]></title>
    <link href="http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/30/13-Mind-Dump/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-30T20:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://christopherjones.us/aom/2014/05/30/13-Mind-Dump</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 13: Perform a mind dump of everything you’re worried about. From the leaky dishwasher to your family member’s poor health — get it all out. Dwight D. Eisenhower did it, and it significantly helped him manage his stress. Just as your body needs to… cleanse itself of waste, so does your mind every once in a while. Getting all your stressors on paper may alleviate some of that pressure. Use <a href="http://wiki.43folders.com/index.php/Trigger_List">David Allen’s GTD trigger</a> list to help you out.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;m reading through this list and I think this could get quite long.  I guess just starting is the way to go.</p>

<p>About the professional side of the house, I have only one project that I&rsquo;ve started which I need to finish and that is my Pomodoro webpage.  It is mostly done but I want to publish it before I consider it done.  I am planning on starting a documentation project for my new position.</p>

<p>I can&rsquo;t recall any commitments or promises to anyone in this list.  The closes that I can think of would be that I need to organize and develop a list of bullets for my supervisor.</p>

<p>I have only one professional communication to make and that is in relation to my upcoming business trip.  I need to make contact with them and confirm arrangements.</p>

<p>Under this planning/organizing heading, I do need to formalize my position goals and objectives with my team lead.  I&rsquo;m not sure what is expected of my job-wise.</p>

<p>I need to reset my voicemail password.</p>

<p>I need to find someone with the key to my drawers.</p>

<p>Under the professional development, one of the bullets is skills to learn.  Since I have more skills to learn at work than I can remember, I&rsquo;ll just write that there are many.</p>

<p>This also reminds me that I wanted to write a resume and have it approved.</p>

<p>Professional wardrobe: I need to get new ribbons, preferably the pre put together ones.  I think there is a link to the website off the BX page.</p>

<p>Starting in on the Personal section.</p>

<p>There are several personal projects that I&rsquo;ve started and not finished:  Ruby Koans, CodeSchool learning Ruby, Wheels Across Anchorage (still), a website redesign, and making beer labels.</p>

<p>Although, I suppose that making beer labels could fall under not started since all I have done it buy the labels, I haven&rsquo;t done anything else.</p>

<p>The only commitment I can recall is to go on a cruise with Hilary.  The next step of which is decide on a cruise and submit the paperwork for it.</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t have any projects for other organizations but I do have an obligation to the SPCA to attend the volunteer session in June.</p>

<p>Communication to make: Call Yarmuth about White House and Capitol building tours.</p>

<p>The next big upcoming event will be Hilary&rsquo;s birthday in August.  Well, on this list, I suppose that I would count Nikki and Max&rsquo;s wedding, the trip to Rehobeth beach, Brandon and Kelsey&rsquo;s visit, and my Mom&rsquo;s visit, followed finally by our cruise.</p>

<p>Bills need to be paid for June since I won&rsquo;t be here.  I wonder if I can look up balances for most of them?</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m waiting on several packages the most important of which is probably my text book for my class starting in June.</p>

<p>Need to buy Windows 8 for my desktop and possibly another HDD.</p>

<p>I need to drop my blues off at the dry cleaners.</p>

<p>Now that I have made it through the list, there is still one big stress on my mind that I don&rsquo;t think has made enough of an impact on this post.  I am leaving for a business trip this week and I am super nervous about it.  I just found out Friday that I will be actually going on it.  It has really reworked my whole little world.  I really hope that Hilary does alright during the time that I am gone.  Since she doesn&rsquo;t drive and seems hesitant to take the bus/MARC, I&rsquo;m worried that she will sit at home all three weeks that I am gone.  All I can do is hope that she doesn&rsquo;t.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
