<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 52in52 | Chris W Jones]]></title>
  <link href="http://magikid.github.io/blog/categories/52in52/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://magikid.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-18T21:01:21-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://magikid.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chris W Jones]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[chris@christopherjones.us]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating an API]]></title>
    <link href="http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/03/18/creating-an-api/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-18T19:25:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/03/18/creating-an-api</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, I have been working hard to add an <abbr title="Application Programming Interface">API</abbr> to a website that I wrote.  I&rsquo;m going to explain what an API is and why I want one for this website.</p>

<p>When you visit a website, your browser uses a protocol called HTTP.  HTTP is made up of verbs that describe interactions with the server.  When you visit <a href="http://christopherjones.us"><a href="http://christopherjones.us">http://christopherjones.us</a></a>, your browser uses the HTTP verb GET because you want to &ldquo;get&rdquo; the page.  When you log in to a website, your browser uses the verb POST like you&rsquo;re mailing the data to the server.  There are a bunch of other verbs used as well but I&rsquo;m not going to get into them.  After doing a GET request, the server located at <a href="http://christopherjones.us"><a href="http://christopherjones.us">http://christopherjones.us</a></a> responds with the page you requested, its response will look something like:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='html'><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;html&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="ni">&amp;lt;</span>head<span class="ni">&amp;gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="ni">&amp;lt;</span>title<span class="ni">&amp;gt;</span>Chris W Jones<span class="ni">&amp;lt;</span>/title<span class="ni">&amp;gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="ni">&amp;lt;</span>/head<span class="ni">&amp;gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="ni">&amp;lt;</span>body<span class="ni">&amp;gt;</span>...<span class="ni">&amp;lt;</span>/body<span class="ni">&amp;gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Believe it or not, that response is hard for a computer to read.  The difficulty comes from the fact that anything can be in between those <code>&lt;body&gt;</code> tags.  It could be a picture of a cat or it could be the entire text of the Illiad.  Computers don&rsquo;t do so well with that much ambigity which is why developers use APIs.  APIs are the computer&rsquo;s interface to a website.</p>

<p>When designing an API, developers think about what kinds of information that users will want to use from their site.  For example in my Bibliophilum website, I might have an API endpoint that allows users to request the books in their library.  Another endpoint might allow users to see which books are currently loaned from their library.  When a user wants the list of their books, they&rsquo;ll do a GET request to that endpoint and the server will respond with something that a computer can understand like:</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='json'><span class='line'><span class="err">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">&lt;p&gt;</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="err">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;</span><span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">id:</span> <span class="err">1,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">title:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Moby Dick&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">author:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Herman Melville&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">},</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">id:</span> <span class="err">2,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">title:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Accelerando&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="err">author:</span> <span class="nt">&quot;Charles Stross&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">&lt;p&gt;</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="err">&lt;/p&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">&lt;p&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>The format of the response from the server is usually documented and doesn&rsquo;t change.  This allows the computer using the API to understand the data received.</p>

<p>I really wanted to develop an API for this website because of a new trend in web development.  This trend is towards using a single page to serve the whole website and requesting the different pages in the background.  Gmail is a good example of a single page application (SPA) like this.</p>

<p>In the traditional client/server architecture, your browser sends a GET request to my server.  My server responds with the page.  You click the link which sends another GET request for that page which my server responds with.  In the SPA architecture, your browser sends a GET request for my main page.  After that, when you click a link on the page the page rewrites itself to be the new page, requesting additional data from the server as needed.</p>

<p>The main benefit of using this SPA is that the processing power my server would use to generate the page is offloaded to your browser saving me bandwidth and electricity.  The API comes into this when the SPA requets additional data as needed.  It needs to be able to understand the data so it queries the API.</p>

<p>That is an overview of what APIs are and one way that they&rsquo;re used.  Next week, I&rsquo;m going to explore a specific way to implement an API in Rails using a gem called Grape.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Busy Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/03/12/busy-life/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-12T21:01:25-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/03/12/busy-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Life Is getting busy for me. In about two weeks my wife, Hilary, and I will be moving. In addition to that, I have an astronomy class that just finished and a discrete math class that starts on Monday. I also have a busy schedule when I&rsquo;m at work.</p>

<p>This isn&rsquo;t the first time that I have found the pace of life picking up.  I have found that when I get stressed out about having a lot on my plate, the best thing I can do is control what I can and try to not let the rest bother me.  That means that I have been making schedules and lists for the upcoming move and taking things in stride when the don&rsquo;t work out like I want.  For example, a townhouse that we were interested was pulled off the market the day that we were going to view it. Frustrating.</p>

<p>Two points that I always keep on my schedule though are reading and programming.  Sometimes <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:magikid/t:feedly/">they overlap</a> when I get especially busy. Currently, I&rsquo;m reading <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/913989470">Murder at the Vicarage</a> by Agatha Christie.  It&rsquo;s a little outside my usual genre of hard sci-fi/space opera but I&rsquo;m enjoying it so far.  It&rsquo;s going to be a quick read.</p>

<p>As for programming, I&rsquo;m still working on my bibliophilium site but slowly. I want to start correctly so that I don&rsquo;t get a few months in and wish I had done things differently.  That involves researching implementations.  Also, moving kind of eats into my programming time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Committal]]></title>
    <link href="http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/03/04/projects/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-04T20:13:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/03/04/projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have had a lot of problems with starting projects and not following through.  It took me about a year to work through the Ruby koans <small><a href="http://rubykoans.com/">official site</a>|<a href="https://github.com/magikid/my-ruby-koans">my code</a></small>.  And they were simple programming exercises designed to introduce you to the language.  <strong>I say no more</strong>.</p>

<p>This is the year that I stop starting without finishing, at least where programming is involved.  I have recently started a new project that I intend to be a sort-of showcase for my website building skills.  So far, I just have the idea but I want to start it right from the very beginning.  To that end, before I write a single line of code, I will be writing a <a href="https://github.com/magikid/bibliophilium/wiki/functional-spec">functional spec</a> which lays out the user interaction with the site.  It is much easier to pick out issues with the design when they&rsquo;re just ideas on paper.  This will be completed by next Wednesday (11 March 2015).</p>

<p>An example of when writing a spec first came in handy.  I recently started a new project at work.  It will be a fairly simple site to create but it has some very demanding customers.  Before I started to write the code for their website, I sat down and wrote a spec for their site.  I laid out all the different pages of the website.  I wrote down likely use scenarios for the website.  I put in things that I wouldn&rsquo;t be supporting during development.</p>

<p>One of the customers came to visit me and discuss his ideas for the website.  Because I had already formulated my ideas for user interactions, I was able to show him that we were already on the same page in our thinking.  I was also able to assure him that I didn&rsquo;t want to obliterate his current workflow and destroy his productivity with my design.  The best part for me was not having to completely explain myself to him since I&rsquo;d already done that in the document.  I was able to send him a link and say, read it yourself.</p>

<p>Back to my library project: the idea came for this site came to me because of the lack of decent library software.  No seriously.  Look around if you don&rsquo;t believe me.  I just want a decent website that is mobile friendly to manage my books.  It would be great if it integrated with Amazon to pull in book covers too.  That in a nutshell is my new project.  I will be building a library management website.  I&rsquo;m sure this won&rsquo;t be my last post on the subject.</p>

<p>For the programmers in the audience, here&rsquo;s what my thinking is for that side of the house.  I&rsquo;d love to use modern programming standards for this.  The back end will be coded using my beloved Ruby language.  I haven&rsquo;t decided if I will use a full <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> stack or a Rack application like <a href="https://intridea.github.io/grape/">Grape</a> for the API.  I&rsquo;m planning on using the <a href="http://jsonapi.org/">JSON API</a> standard either way for communication with the front end.  Speaking of, I want to use a javascript framework like <a href="https://angularjs.org/">AngularJS</a> for the front end of the website.  That way the website has a very responsive feel to it.  I also would like to learn more about how to create a full website with AngularJS.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been dabbling around with javascript frameworks for about two weeks now.  I&rsquo;ve tried out both AngularJS and <a href="http://emberjs.com/">EmberJS</a>.  I liked the models aspect of Ember more, especially since Angular doesn&rsquo;t have anything close to models.  But after playing around some and exploring both, I think I&rsquo;m going with Angular because of the support for it.  I think it will be easier to solve any problems that I have with it because of its popularity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Blogging Habit]]></title>
    <link href="http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/02/26/a-blogging-habit/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-26T18:50:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://magikid.github.io/52in52/2015/02/26/a-blogging-habit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was listening to <a href="http://www.developertea.com/">Developer Tea</a> yesterday and they were discussing the merits of having a personal blog and marketing yourself as a developer.  I set this blog up last fall as a spot for me to journal.  I think rather than using it as a journal, I will try to discuss mainly programming related topics from now on.</p>

<p>I will be discussing projects that I&rsquo;m working on and new techniques that I&rsquo;m learning.</p>

<p>This week, I&rsquo;ve been exploring <a href="http://joelonsoftware.com/articles/fog0000000043.html">12 Steps To Better Code</a> by Joel Spolsky.  Going through this list, they don&rsquo;t all make sense for me as a long coder working on a website.  I&rsquo;ll still go through all of them.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ol>
<li><p>Do you use source control?</p>

<p>This one is easy.  Yes, I use source control for all of my projects.  It gives me such peace of mind knowing that when I make a mistake, I can quickly and easily fix it.  My source control of choice is <code>git</code> but I won&rsquo;t hold it against anyone for using <code>hg</code>.</p></li>
<li><p>Can you make a build in one step?</p>

<p>For this question, I&rsquo;m going to say that build means deploy the current version of the site.  The answer to this is yes.  I mainly accomplish this by using the correct tools for the correct language.  When I&rsquo;m writing a traditional rails application, I use the asset pipeline.  When I&rsquo;m writing an angular app, I use yo, bower and grunt.  When I&rsquo;m not writing a web app, I still have a script that builds or runs the application.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you make daily builds?</p>

<p>This one is, I guess, yes.  I make daily builds when I&rsquo;m working on a project, especially for web development.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have a bug database?</p>

<p>Yes.  I tend to use GitHub (or at work GitLab) Issues for bug tracking.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you fix bugs before writing new code?</p>

<p>It depends on the schedule.  Since I&rsquo;m a one-man coding shop, I try to balance new features with backlog fixes.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have an up-to-date schedule?</p>

<p>For loose definitions of schedule, yes.  I try to put estimates on the issues that I open and assign them to milestones which have deadlines.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have a spec?</p>

<p>This is a new one I can answer yes to.  I recently (read last week) started writing a spec for my current project.  I haven&rsquo;t started any coding on it.  One of the stakeholders came over and was talking to me about things he would like to see.  Where we differed, it was so easy to update the spec with his requests.</p></li>
<li><p>Do programmers have quiet working conditions?</p>

<p>Yes. Bose QC15&rsquo;s help a lot.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you use the best tools money can buy?</p>

<p>When I&rsquo;m at home I do.  When I&rsquo;m at work, it&rsquo;s a different story.  I have some good tools but I wouldn&rsquo;t say they&rsquo;re the best.  My biggest complaint is that I can&rsquo;t get Sublime Text installed.  I have to resort to using Notepad++.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you have testers?</p>

<p>Not really.  I don&rsquo;t always write tests, unit or otherwise.  I&rsquo;ve tried in the past but since until recently I had to resort to Cygwin, that made writing tests impractical.</p></li>
<li><p>Do new candidates write code during their interview?</p>

<p>Not applicable to me.</p></li>
<li><p>Do you do hallway usability testing?</p>

<p>If my wife counts then yes, I do.  She gets tormented by me when I need an average person to test something.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>In wrapping up, I came up with 11/12 which Joel says is tolerable.  I have to agree.  I can&rsquo;t complain about my programming conditions.  PS for those of you wondering about my cat Leon, he&rsquo;s doing well.  In my last post, he had developed Feline Diabetes.  It turns out that cats can recover from diabetes.  Scientists aren&rsquo;t sure how but that&rsquo;s what happened to Leon.  He is back to his old licky, annoying self.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
